$(document).ready(function() {
  loadQuestion();
});

var timer = 300;
var intervalID, correctAnswer= 0 , wrongAnswer = 0;
$("#questions").hide();


$(".button").on("click", startGame);
$("#endGame").on("click", endGame);

// setTimeout(timeUp, 1000 * 60);

function startGame () {
  decrementTimer();
  $("#questions").show();
  setTimeout(thirtySeconds, 1000 * 270);
}

function thirtySeconds (){
  $("#time-left").append("<h2>");
  alert("Thirty seconds left!");
  // console.log(thirtySeconds);
}

function decrementTimer (){
  intervalID = setInterval(function (){
    timer--;
    if(timer === 0) {
      clearInterval(intervalID);
      endGame();
    }
  }, 1 * 1000)
}

// function timeUp (){
//   $("#time-left").alert("<h2>");
//   alert("Time's Up!");
//   console.log(timeUp);
// }

var array = []

function endGame (){
  $("#questions").hide();
  $('input[type=radio]:checked').each(function(){
    array.push($(this).val());
    // if ($('.answer').is(":checked"))
    // {
    //   console.log($('.answer').val(), 'value');
    // }  // // for(var i=0; i< questions.length; i++){
  
})
// console.log(array);

for (var q = 0; q < questions.length; q++ ) {
  // console.log(questions[q]);
  for (var a = 0; a < questions[q].answer.length; a++) {
    for ( var i = 0; i < array.length; i++) {
      if (questions[q].answer[a] === array[i]) {
        // console.log(questions[q], 'these are correct')
        var response = questions[q]
        // console.log(response)
        // $("#questions").append("Question: " + response);
        $("#correctAnswers").append("Correct answer: " +  response.question +" "+ response.correctAnswer + "<ol>");
        // I was attempting to make each correct answer show up in an ordered list on the final page - got it! :)

        // $("#correctAnswers").css({"font-size": "30px"});
        // $("#correctAnswers").html("<ol>");
      }
    }
  }
}
    // // for(var i=0; i< questions.length; i++){

  //   $(".answer[name='question-"+ i +"']:checked"), function(){
  //     console.log("This is working");
      // if ($(this).val() === questions[i].correctAnswer){
  //       correctAnswer++;
  //       // how to get the correct answers to show up on the screen?
  //     }
  //     else{
  //       wrongAnswer++
  //     }
  //   }
  // }
}


function loadQuestion() {
  for (var i=0; i < questions.length; i++) {
    $("#questions").append("<h1> " + questions[i].question + " </h1>");
    for(var j = 0; j < questions[i].answer.length; j++){
      $("#questions").append("<input type='radio' class='answer' name='question-" +i+ " ' value="+ questions[i].answer[j]+" > " +questions[i].answer[j]);
    }
  };
  
};


var questions = [{
  question: "What is the average weight for a bottle of wine?",
  answer: ["2.65lbs","1.33lbs","5lbs","3lbs","2.1lbs"],
  correctAnswer: "2.65lbs"
},

{
  question:"Where was the first known winery located?",
  answer:["Babylon", "China", "Armenia", "Greece", "Sicily"],
  correctAnswer:"Armenia"
},

{
  question:"The most popular type of white wine is _________",
  answer:["Reisling", "Chardonnay", "Moscato", "Pinot Grigio", "Sauvignon Blanc"],
  correctAnswer:"Chardonnay"
},

{
  question:"True or False: Fortified wines have been distilled to have a greater alcohol content",
  answer: ["True", "False"],
  correctAnswer: "False; Fortified wines have had brandy or another spirit added to them "
},

{
  question:"What kind of French wine is traditionally made from the pinot noir grape?",
  answer:["Beaujolais", "Bordeaux", "Merlot", "Pinot Noir", "Burgundy"],
  correctAnswer:"Burgundy"
},

{
  question:"What was Dom Perignonâ€™s occupation when he invented Champagne?",
  answer:["Carpenter", "Blacksmith", "Monk", "Shoe Cobbler", "Sculptor"],
  correctAnswer:"Monk"
},

{
  question:"How many standard wine bottles equals one Nebuchadnezzar??",
  answer:["20", "15", "12", "6", "25"],
  correctAnswer:"20"
},

{
  question:"True or False: Red wine is made from red grapes, and white wine is made from white grapes",
  answer:["True", "False"],
  correctAnswer:"False; red wine gets its color because the grape skins are left to ferment with the juice. To make white wine, the skins are removed before fermentation."
},

{
  question:"How many varieties of wine grapes exist in the world today?",
  answer:["5,000" , "1,000" , "50,000" , "10,000"],
  correctAnswer:"There are over 10,000 kinds of grapes"
},

{
  question:"When was the corkscrew designed?",
  answer:["1800's", "1900's", "6000 B.C", "1700's"],
  correctAnswer:"It was designed in the mid-1800s"
}];


